pubsub.com 2003-06-25

# PubSub.com: Privacy Policy

We at PubSub are committed to the following principles to protect your privacy: 

  1. Your personal details (your e-mail address, username, password) are never given to a third party without your express and explicit permission.
  2. Privacy FAQs and Other Questions
    * What personal details does PubSub need to know?  

    * When is my information given out?  

    * How are my personal details used?  

    * Does PubSub sell my information to third parties?  

    * Is your service secure?  

    * Will I be added to any mailing texts?  

    * Do you send unsolicited emails?  

    * What do you use cookies for?  

    * How do you notify me of any changes?  

    * How do I cancel my account?  

    * How do I contact you?  

**Your personal details are never given to a third party without your express and explicit permission.**

  * We will never sell or give your email address to third parties unless you say so.  

  * All functionality and services that use your information are fully "opt-in". You only receive information you explicitly ask for, from PubSub. This will not change unless you indicate otherwise.  

  * We will not share your personal information with anyone, including another PubSub user, unless you ask for this to be done.  

[return to top]  
  
**Privacy FAQs and Other Questions**  
  
What personal details does PubSub need to know?   

  * The only information we need to know is your username, password and email address. This is collected so that we can validate that you are who you say you are.   

[return to top]  
  
When is my information given out?  

  * Your information is never given out, unless you explicitly ask for this to be done.  

[return to top]  
  
How are my personal details used?

  * Registration

In order to use this service, you must first complete the registration process. During registration, you are required to give your email address, and choose a username and password. We use this information to verify you have entered your own email address by sending a confirmation email that activates the account. We will not share this information with third-parties without your permission.

  * Analysis of aggregated information

PubSub may analyze aggregated information in order to understand the volumes of usage over time and traffic patterns. The information analyzed is not personally identifiable. It helps us to judge what changes we need to make to the service to support it as it grows.

  * Legal Disclaimer

In exceptional circumstances, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or a legal process served on our Web site.

  * No. We do not sell, give or exchange your information with anyone else unless you say we can. 

  * PubSub uses a number of security features to ensure that malicious users are not able to gain access to your information. This includes encryption methods for sending information over the web, similar to that used by banks. Our servers are also locked within a secured building, giving access to only specific PubSub employees. 

  * No. Again, PubSub will never divulge any information to mailing texts unless you ask us explicitly to do so. 

  * You will receive emails from PubSub on very rare occasions. We send all new members a welcoming email to verify that they are who they say they are. 
  * Service improvement information will be sent via email. We will not send any 3rd party marketing material to users in email, unless a user has requested such information. On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email alert. We may from time to time alert users to new functionality available to them within the application. Other messages people may receive from time to time include: 

\- Updates to software

\- New services

\- Messages people have requested to receive

  * A cookie is a piece of data sent by us as part of responses to your browser's requests and may be stored on your computer by your browser. In order to enhance privacy and security we use cookies to ensure that other sites cannot see your information in referrer records. We store a cookie on your machine to identify you when you use PubSub services. This means you do not have to input your username and password every time you use PubSub.
  * In order for us to measure volumes and usage of the system, we use two types of 'cookies'. These also enable us to make better estimations about the infrastructure required to support the service as it grows. Your cookie can be read only by servers in the domain from which the cookie was sent. We use both 'session' cookies and 'persistent' cookies. Session cookies are stored on your machine while you use the site in order to make it possible for you to use the service efficiently, and are deleted once you close your browser software. Persistent cookies stay on your machine and will contain information about when and how often the service is used. You will be able to access all services even if you choose to reject cookies by changing the settings in your browser. 

Log Files 

We will also use log files to record all activity on our servers. We do this to detect attempts to attack the system. We also do this so we can study the logs and understand usage of the system and to enhance service in the future. Technical data held in log files includes your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider ("ISP"), referring/exit Web pages, computer platform type, date/time stamp, and user activity. PubSub uses the log data to administer the Services and the Site and gather broad usage information for aggregate use. 

  * If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement on the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we may disclose it. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

  * You can cancel your membership by sending an email to [info@pubsub.com](mailto:cancel@PubSub.com). If a user deactivates their account, that user's information is deleted from our machines immediately. However, customer records may still exist on back-up tapes, but PubSub will never intentionally restore your data to an operational status once you have cancelled your account. 

  * If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at [info@pubsub.com](mailto:info@PubSub.com)

For any other information, please send an email to [info@pubsub.com](mailto:info@PubSub.com)

Best regards,

The PubSub team

[return to top]
